americancentury.com 2004-12-05

# American Century | Privacy & Security

Privacy & Security   
It's a Matter of Privacy — Yours   
Trust is the foundation of any relationship. At American Century, trust takes on even greater importance. After all, when you entrust your money to our care, you also entrust us with your goals, plans and perhaps even your dreams for your financial future. We take that responsibility seriously. We work hard to do the right thing – by striving to provide solid value, excellent investment management and the best service possible. We apply that same integrity to protecting your privacy. 

  * We do not sell your personal information to anyone.
  * Because we limit our use of your personal information, there is no opportunity for you to opt out of third party sharing.
  * The service providers with whom we share personal information are not authorized to use it for any purpose other than to assist American Century.

Our Privacy and Security Policy is divided into the following sections:

  * What Types of Information Do We Collect?
  * How Do We Use the Information We Collect?
  * Do We Use This Information for Marketing?
  * How Do We Protect Your Information?
  * Our Use of Cookies and Clear Gifs 
  * Secure Online Account Access
  * Web Browser Requirements
  * Contacting American Century
  * Notification of Changes

What Types of Information Do We Collect? | back to top  
   
The information we collect about you generally falls into one of the following categories. 

  * Information, such as your address, Social Security number, phone number, bank information, income, net worth and investment profile, which you may provide in account applications and other forms you submit to us. 
  * Account information, such as your fund choices, account balances and transaction history. 
  * Personal information about you, such as age, gender and marital status, that consumer reporting agencies and other organizations may provide to us. 
  * Information relating to your use of our Web site, such as your User Name, Password, failed attempts to log in and the last time you logged in.

Also, when you conduct business with American Century online, you may notice our use of Internet "cookies." See our discussion below of cookies and how we use them.   
  
How Do We Use the Information We Collect? | back to top  
   
We use the information we collect primarily to maintain your accounts and process your transactions. In doing so, we may share this information with other financial service companies in the American Century corporate family, such as the funds' transfer agent, distributor and investment advisor. We also may share this information with outside companies that we hire to perform administrative services on our behalf. 

Examples include transaction processing and servicing organizations, including our clearing broker, that administer transactions you request or authorize, and print and mail service providers that assist us in distributing materials such as transaction confirmations, annual reports, prospectuses and tax forms. We also may share this information with others under certain limited circumstances permitted by law, such as to resolve a dispute or prevent fraud. When required by law, we may need to disclose personal information where such action is deemed necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on americancentury.com.   
  
Do We Use This Information for Marketing? | back to top  
   
American Century's vision, which drives all our company activities, is to help people achieve their dreams. We do rely on the information we collect to help us better understand you and your investing needs. This allows us to offer investment products and services that may be of interest to you. From time to time we may share this information with other financial service companies in the American Century corporate family and with others we hire to help us with our research efforts, mailings or other American Century marketing or communications activities. 

In the next section of this policy, we explain how we protect your information. If, after reading that section, you choose to opt out of future marketing mailings, you may do so in one of the following ways.

  * Mailing your request to:  
American Century Investments  
P.O. Box 419200  
Kansas City, MO 64141-1816  

  * Calling 1-800-345-2021  
Monday through Friday, 7 a.m. to 7 p.m.  
or Saturday, 9 a.m. to 2 p.m. Central time  

  * Unsubscribe from Email for Individual Investors 

How Do We Protect Your Information? | back to top  
   
We treat all personal information we collect as confidential information offered to us solely and exclusively so that we may provide financial products and services for your benefit. 

We do not sell the personal information we collect. The non-American Century service providers with whom we do share personal information are not authorized to use or share it for any purpose other than to assist American Century.

Our policies allow certain individuals to have access to your personal information — those who must have it to service your account. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect this information. We treat information about our former investors with the same care we take with our current investor's information.  

Americancentury.com is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site of www.americancentury.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement they should first contact an Investor Relations Representative through our various Contact Us options. If they do not receive acknowledgment of their inquiry or their inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, they should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Resolution Process. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve user concerns.   
  
Our Use of Cookies and Clear Gifs | back to top  
   
If you conduct business with American Century online, you may notice our use of Internet cookies. Cookies enable our systems to recognize your browser and customize your experience on our Web site and help us better understand how our investors use our Web site. 

What is a cookie?  
A cookie is a small piece of alphanumeric information placed on your computer by the Web site you are visiting. It allows the Web site to remember or recognize your computer during subsequent visits. Although Web sites use cookies for different purposes, one important function is to allow a site to personalize your experience. For example, a cookie can be used to designate start pages within a site, or to indicate an area of interest to you on a Web site. 

What types of cookies do Web sites put on my computer?   

  * Temporary – Cookies that are stored on your computer only during your browsing session, and are automatically deleted from your computer when you close your browser. No information is collected from your computer. 
  * Persistent – Cookies that are stored on your computer and are not deleted when you close your browser. Permanent cookies retain your preferences for a particular Web site, allowing those preferences to remain for future browsing sessions. No information is collected from your computer.

How does American Century use cookies?  
We use cookies to facilitate your use of our Web site. These cookies do not collect or contain any personally identifiable information. Examples of how we use cookies include:  

|   
---  
| Where a Cookie is Used | Cookie Type | Description  
---|---|---  
All Secure Pages | Temporary | American Century and Pershing, our clearing agent for brokerage customers, use temporary cookies on all secure pages. These cookies store a session ID that is not personally identifiable to you, allowing you to move from page to page without having to log in repeatedly.  
All Pages | Persistent | This cookie analyzes online behavior within our Web site and provides information to help build a better site for our customers. It also provides information about areas of the site where customers are having difficulty completing a function, thus allowing us to improve the site.  
All Secure Pages within Rollover Advisor | Temporary | Financial Engines Advisors, L.L.C., engaged by American Century to provide investment services, uses a cookie to provide a secure session while using their online tool. This cookie stores a session ID on your PC that is not personally identifiable to you.  
Investment Professionals | Persistent | This cookie allows investment professionals the ability to subsequently log in to this part of our site without using a User Name and Password.  
Brokerage Model Portfolio | Persistent | This cookie is set by Pershing to collect browser information for use with their Model Portfolio service. It allows you to access your Model Portfolio during subsequent visits.  
Investment Professionals | Persistent | This cookie allows investment professionals the ability to subsequently log in to this part of our site without using a User Name and Password.  
Home Page | Persistent | This cookie is set by American Century and allows customers to bypass the corporate homepage when they indicate a preference for a section of the site they would like to view on future visits.  
  
What is a Clear Gif and How Are They Used?  
A clear gif, also known as a Web Beacon, is similar in function to cookies. It is a tiny graphic with a unique identifier that is invisible on the page and much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs track online web movements of our users and inform us what content is effective. Clear gifs are not tied to users' personal information.

In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know when they have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to understand the effectiveness of our communications and tailor future emails to meet user needs. 

Users may choose to opt-out of these emails through the following link.

Unsubscribe from Email for Individual Investors

We also use a third party tracking service who sets cookies on our site to track the usage of our Web site. The third party tracking service reports this data to use in aggregate so we can better understand our users and to improve our site. This information is not tied to any individual user.   
  
Secure Online Account Access | back to top  
   
Web Security and You   
Protecting your privacy and security is a shared responsibility. We affirm our commitment to safeguard your personal information; however, it is imperative that you protect your Password to prevent unauthorized access to your accounts. For this reason, we strongly suggest that you do not share your Password with anyone. If you do choose to give it to someone, such as a so-called "financial aggregator" that combines information about you from multiple sources over the Internet, you do so at your own risk. We cannot be responsible for any losses you may incur as a result. 

Users who are concerned about access to their personal information online can update that information, including their User Name and Password, within their personal homepage. 

Mutual Fund and Brokerage Customers  
Registration is the unique User Name and Password combination used to log in to a secure and customized Personal Homepage containing your American Century accounts and other services. Any personal or financial information you provide during the Registration process is kept confidential, as stated in this Privacy and Security Policy. 

To help protect your personal information, American Century employs the following security mechanisms when setting up a Registration account. 

You will be required to create a User Name that must contain six to 20 characters; Cannot contain spaces or special characters (&, %, *, etc.); Case sensitive; capitalization matters. You will be required to create a Password that must include at least two numbers and two letters; Must contain six to 10 characters; Cannot contain spaces or special characters (&, %, *, etc.); Cannot be the same as your User Name; Cannot contain four consecutive numbers from your Social Security number or Employer Identification number; Case sensitive; capitalization matters. A timeout feature will automatically end your secure session if you are not active for 20 minutes. To restart your Registration session, you will need to log in again. After three failed attempts to log in, we lock the account to prevent access to personal information within the Web site.

Investment Professionals  
ProPIN is a separately assigned User ID and Access Code combination for investment professionals. It is used to log in to a secure and customized Personal Homepage containing exclusive information created to help investment professionals help their clients. Any personal information you provide in the Investment Professional Enrollment form is kept confidential, as stated in this Privacy and Security Policy.

Forgotten Passwords or Locked Accounts  
If you forgot your Password or locked your account, American Century can help to re-establish your Internet session.

  * Mutual Fund accounts, Brokerage accounts and Company Sponsored Retirement Plans- Go to Help on any page of our Web site and choose Forgot Password, then follow the steps to answer your Security Question. 
  * Investment Professionals - Call 1-800-345-6488 for assistance with your ProPIN Password.

Our Representatives can be reached Monday through Friday, 7 a.m. to 7 p.m. or Saturday, 9 a.m. to 2 p.m. Central time.  
  
Web Browser Requirements | back to top  
   
We require users to access their accounts online with [Netscape](http://www.netscape.com/computing/download/index.html?cp=hom07x4) (version 6.0 or later), [Microsoft Internet Explorer](http://www.microsoft.com/windows/ie/default.asp) (version 4.0 or later), [Mozilla](http://www.mozilla.org/) (version 1.7 or later) or AOL (for Windows 7.0 or later). These browsers use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology with RSA Public Key encryption. This technology helps enable the security of your online sessions. 

If for any reason your session is no longer secure, you will be disconnected from online account access.

If a session is secure, it means that it is encrypted. Every secure page on American Century's Web site has been secured with a digital certificate by RSA Data Security, Inc. We use SSL, RSA Public Key encryption and proprietary encryption algorithms to secure your connection when you are accessing your account online. American Century supports 128-bit encryption to provide you with secure access to your account information. If your browser does not support 128-bit encryption, we recommend that you upgrade your browser to a newer version. Please access the [ Netscape](http://www.netscape.com/computing/download/index.html?cp=hom07x4), [Microsoft Internet Explorer](http://www.microsoft.com/windows/ie/default.asp) or [Mozilla](http://www.mozilla.org/) Web sites to upgrade your browser to the current version with 128-bit encryption. 

Use the information in the chart below to help you determine the security features within your browser.  

To view the encryption certificate, click on the image of the closed lock or the solid key on the bottom bar of your browser window. A small frame displaying site security information will appear. If you use Internet Explorer, click on the word “Subject” to verify the Web site. If you use Netscape, click on the “View Certificate” button to see information on the subject and issuer. 

This site may contain links to other sites. American Century is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.  
  
Contacting American Century | back to top  
   
American Century believes that your privacy should be respected. We appreciate and take seriously your trust in us and your ablitiy to safeqguard your personal information. For more information about our privacy commitment please contact an Investor Relations Representative at 1-800-345-2021 or visit our Contact Us page.  
Notification of Changes | back to top  
   
We will post any changes to this privacy statement so users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any we disclose it. If, however, we are going to use personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to implementing the change.

 **Effective Date of this Policy**  
September 21, 2004
